JEFF JOSE

Data Analyst - Full Stack Developer - Web Designer - Game Developer

(831) 419-0387 / josejeff@yahoo.com / linkedin.com/in/jeff-jose / github.com/josejeff / josejeff.github.io

SUMMARY

I am experienced in predictive modeling, data analysis, and machine learning. I started my career in Epic Systems where I became familiar with the ETL framework and full stack development. I have a Masters in Data Analysis and 5+ years of experience in developing and implementing data-driven solutions. I am familiar with working with sensitive data and have a HIPAA compliance certification. I am highly adaptable to new technologies and software and always ready to learn.

EXPERIENCE

USPS, San Mateo, CA — *Programmer Analyst* July 2020 - Current

- Designed new features for web-based applications based on customer requirements
- Created executive level reports using Tableau and Python
- Designed and developed 150+ executive-level reports using SQL for the data, Java Spring for the framework, tableau for reporting tools, web technologies including jquery and its related libraries to create the front end scripts

Epic Systems, Verona, WI — Software Developer

August 2018 - july 2020

- Enhanced features for the EPIC Healthy Planet module
- Improved performance of nightly SQL scripts from 8 hr 1 hr
- Designed and developed medication features following HIPAA compliance
- Created reports using the Healthy Planet dashboard and their slicerDicer tool to showcase unique data insights
- Developed dashboards to create unique insights for the Healthy Planet quality measures

SKILLS

Web Development: HTML5, CSS, Javascript, PHP, Jquery,

Ajax, Bootstrap, Rest API, XML, JSON

Database: Oracle, SQL server, big data **Languages:** Java, C#, Python, SQL, R

Data Visualization Tools: Tableau, PowerBI, matplotlib

Machine Learning Skills: scikit-learn, deep learning, machine learning, data cleaning, predictive model building, natural language processing, neural network, numpy, pandas, tensorflow

RELATED PROJECTS

League of Legends Win Predictor

Created a multiple linear regression model in Python using player statistics to predict the likelihood of a player winning a game based on the statistics collected from the LOL API. The model was able to accurately predict a win or loss with an 82% accuracy.

Stock Market Pattern Predictor

Created a time series analysis model using stock data for AMD from 1970 to current day to predict future stock prices. The model was created using python, sci-kit, numpy, pandas, and tensorflow. The model was able to predict the range of future stock prices with a 95% accuracy.

Tableau Report for Sales Information

Created a tableau report able to check Key Performance Indicators (KPI) and see the impact based on state, customer income, and number of customers with relevant filters to see impact across various fields. Used unique features like the geographical chart to provide clear insight into various features.

EDUCATION

SJSU, San Jose, CA — B.S. Computer Science

WGU, Salt Lake City, UT — M.S. Data Analytics